

# Madalina-Eleonora Gheorghe

F, 24 years (Apr 9, 1997)

P Bucharest, Romania

+40768792728

https://madalinaeleonora.dev







I am Madalina and I gathered my passions in Web Development. I'm a Bucharest-based software engineer specialised in building (and occasionally designing) digital experiences. I work in a proactive way, every time ready to face challenges and working well under pressure. I am creative and my analytical thinking is helping me to find solutions for difficult situations. I believe in teams and if we work together and have fun, we can touch even the hardest achievements.

Former Junior Front-End Developer at IBM iX and Database Administrator at Groupe Renault, actually Front-End Developer at Deloitte Digital, focused on increasing both technical and soft skills, working with people around the globe and learning how to deliver their expectations.

# **Technologies**

HTML / CSS	Advanced	5 years
SCSS	Intermediate	3 years
Bootstrap	Intermediate	1 years
JQuery	Intermediate	2 years
JavaScript (including ES6)	Advanced	5 years
Vue.js	Advanced	4 years
VUEX	Intermediate	4 years
Vuetify	Intermediate	4 years
Angular 5+	Advanced	3 years
RxJs	Intermediate	6 months
TypeScript	Intermediate	3 years
Ionic	Medium	6 months
Angular Material	Intermediate	1 years
Adobe Experience Manager	Beginner	1.5 years
VirtualBox	Beginner	1.5 years
Postman	Intermediate	2 years
Git	Intermediate	4 years
Microsoft, Google APIs	Intermediate	1 years
NoSQL (Firebase, Firestore)	Intermediate	2 years
React.js	Beginner	3 months
Carbon	Beginner	3 months

## **Employment**

Deloitte Digital - Frontend Developer / Consultant - (Oct 2021 - Present)

#### Overall responsibilities

- I analyze and study the aspects of the program, decide the objectives to be achieved;
- I design and implement quality applications, using technologies specific to each project, being up to date with news in the field:
- I test the made product and I make the adequate documentation;
- I perform maintenance for existing projects;
- I make objective proposals for development and design;
- I communicate with clients and their representatives, I identify clients' needs and propose optimal solutions to them, participating in all meetings;
- I constantly participate in professional training courses and provide mentoring for other colleagues.
- 1. Client 1 United Arab Emirates (Oct 2021 to date)

Industry: Banking

Technologies: Angular

- Integrate <u>Alpha</u> platform;
- Collaborate with backend developers to improve usability.

### IBM - Frontend Developer - (Dec 2018 - Oct 2021)

### Overall responsibilities

- Develop Web based applications including UX design, application building and supporting solutions;
- Collaborate with back-end developers and web designers to improve usability;
- Get feedback from, and build solutions for, users and customers;
- Create quality mockups and prototypes;
- Stay up-to-date on emerging technologies;
- Participate in shadowing sessions with Senior Front End Developers in solving different problems;
- Create new components and features for the application in a way that we can reuse them when it's need;
- Help both design and development departments to take decisions in order to deliver the best features;
- Participate in every meeting and decision in a proactive way in order to deliver a quality and clean code which meets the client requirements.
- 2. Internship (Dec 2018 Feb 2019)

Technologies: Angular, RxJs, Vue.js, Vuex, Firebase, Ionic

- During the internship I learned the basics of Ionic and Angular, applying the knowledge in a project delivered to the client. Designing mobile-based features, working in an agile team.
- 3. Client 1 (Mar 2019 Mar 2020)

Industry: Inssurance

Technologies: Angular, Ionic, Sass, TypeScript, REST, Capacitor, RxJs

- I investigated and solved some vulnerabilities from the applications;

- I contributed actively on a project from march and until the end of November, by helping other colleagues with code review and implementing reusable components. I also helped taking decisions in business rules and in development process;
- I participated in every meeting and decision in a proactive way in order to deliver a quality and clean code
  which meets the client requirements. I also suggested various changes to the design that was taken into
  account.
- 4. Client 2 (Mar 2020) Industry: Retail

Technologies: React.js

- I participated in discussions with the design and front-end team in order to clarify and suggest edits so the user can have a better experience using the website;
- I created reusable pages using React.js which corresponds to the design;
- I created dynamic forms using Formik framework for the registration of new plastic free materials.
- 5. Client 3 (April 2020 Oct 2021)

Industry: Retail

Technologies: Angular, Sass, TypeScript, REST, RxJs, Adobe Experience Manager, VirtualBox

- I created new components and features for the application in a way that we can reuse them when it's need;
- I helped both design and development departments to take decisions in order to deliver the best features;
- I learned better ways to solve the problems that appears during the development;
- Delivered a feature that wants to improve the customer experience regarding the promotional codes;
- Delivered a feature that wants to help customers to find easier the products already bought in the past.

Groupe Renault – Drive your future practicant - (Jun 2017 – Sept 2017)

Overall responsibilities

- Database maintenance using my own Matlab scripts.

## **Education**

Master's degree in Information Technology Administration and Management, May 2020

Romanian-American University

Grade: 9.66

Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology Administration and Management, May 2015

Romanian-American University

Grade: 9.5

### **Licences & Certifications**

- Think like a hacker (IBM) Issued Sep 2021 See credential
- Watson and Cloud Foundations (IBM) Issued Jan 2021 See credential
- IBM Mentor (IBM) Issued Dec 2020 See credential
- JavaScript Front End Development (IBM) Issued Dec 2020 See credential
- ES SET English Certificate (EF Standard English Test) Issued Jul 2020 See credential
- Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner (IBM) Issued Mar 2020 See credential
- IBM Agile Explorer (IBM) Issued Mar 2020 See credential

# Software projects

- Personal website: <u>madalinaeleonora.dev</u> (for additional information and projects)
- Learning League (Nov 2020). Education application created using Vue.js CLI version 2.6.11 with Vuetify. Video and voice calling are made through CometChat and data is saved through Firebase See project
- University Rating (Jul 2018 Jul 2020). Application for searching and rate universities from Romania. This project
  was created using Angular CLI with TypeScript, Angular Material, Microsoft Text Analytics, Google Maps API,
  Google Charts and RxJs. For database used to store the data is Firebase Firestore See project
- Exams Schedule (Apr 2020 May 2020). Application that allows the management of university exams, created using React.js, axios, Redux, Sass and Firebase Realtime Database See project
- Johnny'z website (May 2019 Oct 2019). Website created using WordPress, the result of a faculty project and currently used as the official site of Johnny'z restaurants See project
- TeachMe (May 2019). Mobile application created using Vue.js, Vuex, Ionic and Firebase which helps you learn new things by taking several courses - <u>See project</u>
- PhotoBooking (Apr 2019). Application that recommends a suitable photographer for a customer's event, according to his visual preferences, budget and period. Application created using Vue.js, Vuetify, Vuex, Firebase -See project
- SmileSharing (Mar 2019). Ride sharing application created using HTML, Vue.js, Vuetify, JavaScript and Google Maps - See project
- RapJobs (Nov 2018). Help candidates find the employer that best suits their needs and personality, using our personality test - <u>See project</u>
- Waffic (Mar 2018 Jul 2018). Integrated application for tracking weather and traffic conditions, using AccuWeather, Google Maps, Google Charts APIs and Firebase Realtime Database - See project
- Event Attendances (Jan 2018 May 2018). Application created using HTML, Vue.js, Element and Firebase. Data is saved through Firebase Database and the login is with Firebase Authentication See project

# Additional experience

#### Languages

- 1. English Full professional proficiency
- 2. Romanian Native or bilingual proficiency

#### Honors and awards

- Second Prize, Rau-DevHack Hackathon (Apr 2019): Awarded 2nd prize for PhotoBooking project.
- First Prize, Web&Mobile Challenge at DevHacks (Nov 2018): Awarded 1st prize for RapJobs project.

#### **Publications**

- JAVA\_HOME to JDK not JRE error? Compiler is not provided on Big Sur? Jun 8, 2021 Medium See publication
- Use any font in your project (and how to define root CSS variables) May 1, 2021 Medium See publication
- Using particles.js as a background with Angular 10 April 30, 2021 Medium See publication
- Git fetch & pull for all repos once April 2, 2021 Medium See publication
- How I personalized my GitHub Overview Jan 8, 2021 Medium See publication
- Providing Security for Client-Server Applications 2019 Research Focus See publication

### Organization

DevAcademy - Trainee - Jun 2018 - Dec 2018

- I was part of the Frontend Track learing HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue.js, REST, Firebase Realtime Database. All the knowledge was applied in different exercises and projects.

## Recommendations

"I worked with Madalina on the same project for over a year. Even though she started as a Junior Developer, she quickly managed to learn and acquire quite an extensive set of skills. Her determination to never give up and always learn and improve, is what sets her apart from many other developers out there. It's been a pleasure working with her. She is currently riding the proverbial wave and I am sure she will achieve great things in the future. I highly recommend her to anyone looking to expand their team(s)." - Theodor Palamaru (Front-End Developer) on LinkedIn.

"For the past years I had the opportunity to work along Madalina on multiple personal & comercial projects. She was able to develop features in an extremely elegant and creative way all the time.

Her ability to develop high quality products while being under extreme pressure is something that I look up to, not only that she's able to stay calm and professional in difficult situations. She's also able to make everyone in the team feel that they are also capable of doing more than they expect from themselves." – Emanuel Cepoi (Full-Stack Developer) on LinkedIn.

"Madalina is always reliable and helping her team members, able to understand the requirements and come up with a solution. It was a joy and always had confidence while working with her. I am strongly recommend her in any new opportunity and challenge." – Raluca Rusu (Project Manager) on LinkedIn.